EMMANUEL TUGBEH, MNCS

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT INFO

Email:etugbeh@outlook.comTelephone:(+234) 8169960927Location:Ajah Lagos 101245, NG

SOCIAL LINKS

 LinkedIn:
 linkedin.com/in/2gbeh

 GitHub:
 github.com/2gbeh

 Figma:
 figma.com/@2gbeh

Kaggle: <u>kaggle.com/emmanueltugbeh</u>

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master's degree (M.Sc.) in Computer
 Science – Advanced Software Engineering
 University of Benin, Edo, NG.
 Apr 2019 - Feb 2021

• Bachelor's degree (B.Sc.) in Mathematics & Computer Science

Benson Idahosa University, Edo, NG. Sep 2010 – Jun 2014

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

- (2021) GoodTalentLabs UI/UX Design Mentor
- (2020) TBLF Virtual Teachers Program
- (2016) PushCV IT/Engineering Specialist
- (2015) HSE 1-3, First Aid & Fire Fighting
- (2014) Google Maps Engine Expert
- (2013) VConnect Hackathon Challenge

SOFT SKILLS

- Resourceful
- Detail Oriented
- Team Player & Mentor

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML 5, CSS 3, AJAX, JQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, Next.js, React Hooks, Redux Toolkit, Next Auth, React Native (Expo), React Query, Vue.js, Nuxt, Java JSP, Java Spring MVC, GraphQL Apollo Client, Material UI (MUI 3), Vuetify, Radix UI, Mantine UI/Hooks, Framer Motion, Formik, Yup, React Hook Form, and Zod.

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, NestJS, PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, Java Servlets, Go, Golang (Gin), GraphQL Apollo Server, React Email, Resend, Prisma, TypeORM, Socket.io, Interswitch, Paystack, Stripe, and Flutterwave.

Testing: Jest, Cypress, Pest, PHPUnit, JUnit, and React Testing Library (RTL).

Database: SQLite, RxDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis Cache, Firebase, and Supabase.

DevOps: Git, GitHub Actions, Vercel, Appwrite, Digital Ocean, CircleCl, Jenkins, NGINX, Linux, AWS (Amazon S3), and Docker.

Others: Slack, Jira, Asana, ClickUp, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access (VBA), Android Studio, NetBeans, IntelliJ IDEA, Kaggle, Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, CorelDraw Graphics Suite, Figma, Google Maps, Google Analytics (GA4), Google Sheets, Google Forms, Peachtree (Sage 50), and SPSS.

CAREER SUMMARY

I'm a self-taught full-stack developer with over 10 years' experience in enterprise software development and IT training. I am a certified Web/Mobile App Developer, Data Analyst and Developer Community Mentor. My tech stacks are; React.js (Next.js), React Native (Expo), Node.js with TypeScript (NestJS), PHP (Laravel), PostgreSQL (Supabase) and AWS (Amazon S3).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full-Stack Engineer (Remote) Cardio Autotech, Lagos, NG.

Car Repairs & Services:

- Created responsive and reusable UI components with Next.js (14.x), TypeScript and TailwindCSS.
- Developed and integrated backend APIs using Node.js (NestJS), GraphQL and PostgreSQL.

Senior Frontend Developer (Remote) Buzzbite.io, London, UK.

Brand Campaign & Influencer Marketplace:

- Created responsive and reusable UI components with React (Next.js).
- Integrated RESTful APIs built with Laravel and MySQL database.
- Integrated payments using Paystack SDK.

Senior Backend Developer (Hybrid) Pear SDC, Edo, NG.

May 2018 - Dec 2020

May 2023 - present

Feb 2021 - Jan 2023

Benson Idahosa University's Admission Portal:

- Created RESTful APIs with Laravel and MySQL database.
- Integrated client-side business logic with Vue.js (Nuxt) and Laravel Blade template (for Admin).
- Integrated payments using Remita payment gateway and Interswitch SDK.

Data Analyst NIIT Benin Centre, Edo, NG.

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018

Technical Skills & Corporate Management Training:

- Created a student attendance and course completion tracking tool with Django REST Framework.
- Taught Data Analytics using Python, Microsoft Power BI and PostrgeSQL database.

Mobile App Developer Appzone Group (Zone), Lagos, NG.

Feb 2013 - Aug 2016

Core Banking Solutions:

- Designed internet banking and mobile app screens for Providus Bank MFB using React Native.
- Built and deployed a customer self-service desktop software at Union Bank, Silverbird Galleria, VI.
- Integrated SAS Anti-Money Laundry (AML) solution at Sterling Bank HQ, Marina/CMS.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Kotlin Developer Community

Mar 2019 – Dec 2021

- Organized weekly developer meet-ups centered around JetBrains products and services.
- Made use of Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA, Android Studio, Figma, Google Sheets and Google Forms.

Google Student Ambassador (GDG)

Jul 2013 - Aug 2014

- Organized weekly developer meet-ups centered around Google products and services.
- Made use of AngularJS, Adobe Dreamweaver, Google Maps, Google Drive and Google Forms.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Odara TV - Tech News, Movies & TV Shows

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AJAX, JSON and GitHub Pages.

2gbeh.github.io/odara-tv

Aladdin RTK – Book Sales & Distribution Management Software

Laravel 8, Bootstrap 5, PHP 7 and MySQL. github.com/2gbeh/rtk

ZEntry – Church Internal Database (PWA)

React.js (18.x), React Query, TypeScript, TailwindCSS and Firebase.

zentry.vercel.app

Fedora – Income & Expense Tracker App

React Native (Expo 50), TypeScript, NativeWind and Appwrite.

github.com/2gbeh/fedora

Marina CMS - Reusable Admin Dashboard

Next.js (14.x), TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Radix UI (Shadcn/ui) and Vercel. marina-cms.vercel.app

Eventra - Event Attendance Tracker (PWA)

Vue.js (3.x), Vuex 4 (Pinia), TypeScript, TailwindCSS and Supabase.

eventra.vercel.app